Julianne VanWagenen

<u>ivanwagenen.github.io</u> | Cambridge, MA, USA | +1 517 505 5057 | jmvanwag@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Program and content development & management in higher-ed, business, and tech; project management; research; academic journal editorial and management; 15+ years experience in web design & ed program creation/coordination; detail-oriented self-starter who enjoys and excels at problem solving in a team environment

SKILLS

Interpersonal Communication Team building & Collaboration Academic Research and Writing Attention to Detail Project Management Strategic & Organizational Planning Meaningful Goal-driven Content Creation Problem Solving Qualitative & Quantitative Research Presentations & Public Speaking Adobe Suite, HTML, CSS Foreign Languages

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Digital Data Design Institute at Harvard (D^3)

Program Content Manager, Insights and Experiences

Boston, MA September 2024 – Present

- Lead Insights team production of general-public articles based on academic research on technology in business
- Manage development and production of learning content and programs that amplifies the work of D^3, using HeyGen, Sana, Wordpress, and the Adobe Suite
- Work closely with institute faculty and industry experts to develop learning content, including interviews, webinars, blog posts, and short videos.
- Liaise with lab support staff (post-docs, lab managers, research associates) to ensure development of a suite of learning network offerings for each lab with appropriate levels of audience engagement.
- Develop and implement standard operating procedures for program delivery and recommend improvements as opportunities arise.
- Manage large and complex virtual programming

Pirandello in Translation - Stories for a Year

Web Developer, Translator (pirandellointranslation.org)

2021 - Present

- Designed and built the book-project website, which hosts a growing number of original Pirandello translations
- Worked with a team to create project goals, wire-frame design, take feedback, and build consensus to finalize
- Continue to work with a team to coordinate translation and presentation of digital publication of translations

HBS Online, Harvard Business Analytics Program

Boston, MA

Online Learning Manager

July 2022 - August 2024

- Managed courses and seminars on an online course platform: included liaising with faculty and TFs, updating course content, coordinating online and in-person synchronous content
- Produced videos and graphics, using the Adobe Suite, for social media and asynchronous program content
- Accessibility lead; supplemental programming lead (developed and managed)

Harvard University

Postdoctoral Fellow

Cambridge, MA January 2022 – July 2022

- Book project proposal selected from a wide group of candidates from around the world
- Work on research and publishing related to countercultural song, modern mythologies, mass tourism, and travel ethics; have published and peer-reviewed book and articles (see below).

Pirandello in Translation - Stories for a Year

Web Developer, Translator (pirandellointranslation.org)

2021 – Present

- Designed and built the book-project website, which hosts a growing number of original Pirandello translations
- Worked with a team to create project goals, wire-frame design, take feedback, and build consensus to finalize
- Continue to work with a team to coordinate translation and presentation of digital publication of translations

Pirandello Society of America

Web Developer (pirandellosociety.org)

2019 - 2023

- Designed and built the literary-society and academic-journal website
- Worked with a team to create project goals, wire-frame design, take feedback, and build consensus to finalize

The Pirandello Society Annual Journal

Managing Editor

2017 - 2023

- Design and build each the annual journal using InDesign; create cover designs in Gimp

- Copy-edit the content and formatting for the entire journal
- Work with the content editors to come to a consensus on cover design and other formatting questions
- Prepare journal for printer; communicate with printer across the entire process to assure print accuracy

Tsinghua University Instructor, Thesis Advisor

Beijing, China Fall 2018 - Fall 2021

- Created and taught courses in the Institute of World Literatures and Cultures: "Journey to Italy: Travel Writing since the Grand Tour", "Rereading the Divine Comedy with Borges", "Postcolonial Literature in the 1900s"
- Instituted an initiative in sophomore seminars that helped students to excel in academic writing
- Worked on a team to organize the curriculum of IWLC in terms of pedagogical and content goals and program continuity as well as a graduate school application workshop
- Advised senior-theses; organized time, set deliverable dates; advised on research, citational styles, clarity

University of Southern California

Los Angeles, CA Spring 2018

Lecturer

Taught 3 courses in Italian language, worked with a team to create and grade bi-weekly assessments

Worked with a team to create a community-based component to courses; facilitated weekly language table

Milan and Siena: Harvard Summer School Study Abroad

Coordinator, Instructor

Summer 2016, Summer 2017

- Worked on a team to develop and teach the language-program courses for a new study-abroad program
- Worked with a team to organize the housing, field trips, events, reservations for a group of 30 undergraduates
- Led 2 sections of 8-credit Aesthetics & Ethics course taught during the summer abroad

Monad Media

Cambridge, MA 2014 - 2017

Owner, Project Manager

- Founded company that provided economical web development to academic projects
- Worked with creative teams in Harvard GSAS and Libraries to create wire frames and manage web development
- Led project management, including timelines, deadlines, cost analysis, bug fixes, etc., for all projects

metaLAB (at) Harvard

Cambridge, MA

2013 - 2017

Project Manager, Principal Investigator

- Participated as a creative lead in metaLAB principal meetings; wrote grant applications for various projects
- Worked with a team of professors to create interdisciplinary courses (offered FAS and GSD); created syllabi, created and taught innovate discussion-sections/studios; organized summer developer workshops and new digital-humanities projects
- Project manager for curarium.com; managed developer team using Redmine, worked with advisors at the Berkman Klein Center, tracked deadlines and bug fixes, presented platform at conferences and workshops

Harvard University Course Developer, Instructor, Thesis Advisor Cambridge, MA 2013 - 2017

Developed and taught courses in in the Romance Languages and Literatures department

- Wrote grant applications; won 2017 Elson Family Arts Initiative Fund to Support Arts in Curricula
- Won the Harvard University Department of Romance Languages and Literatures Teaching Prize in 2016
- Won the Derek Bok Center for Teaching and Learning Certificate of Excellence for every semester I was eligible
- Organized Chiasmi Graduate Student Conference in 2013
- Presented at panels or invited talks and/or organized and chaired panels at over 20 conferences and events

Dudley House Library

Cambridge, MA

2012 - 2017

2011 - 2017

Hired and managed a team of between 5 and 8 librarians; managed library with team

Harvard University Doctoral Researcher

Head Librarian

Cambridge, MA

Completed my doctoral work on time and with a successful dissertation that was published in 2023

- 2013-14 Video Coordinator for Colloquium series; coordinated and managed production of video interviews
- Copy-edited various projects, for example, Johanna Drucker's *Graphesis* (2014)
- Worked as a translator for the Italian cantautori in Translation website theitaliansong.com

The American in Italia Magazine

Rome, Italy 2009 - 2014

Columnist

Met monthly deadlines, worked with editor to revise, copy edit; published over 40 articles

Physical Chemistry Department, Michigan State University

East Lansing, MI

L'università Roma Tre, Biology Program

September 2007 - June 2008

- Created a website (Dreamweaver) for the PI's research project on the dipole moment of white-dwarf stars
- Wrote programs in Terminal that ran on the university super computer and simulated how molecules would act when put under the intense atmospheric pressure of a white-dwarf star; collected/organized all post-run data

EDUCATION

Harvard University - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences
PhD, Italian Studies

September 2011 - May 2017

DePaul University - Honors College
BA, with High Honors, Double Major in Italian Studies and English Literature

Additional Study

Cambridge, MA
September 2011 - May 2017

Chicago, IL
September 2002 - March 2006

Roma, Italy

LANGUAGES

English (native), Italian (near-native), Spanish (intermediate), French (basic)

SOFTWARE

Adobe Creative Suite (Premiere, Express, Dreamweaver, InDesign, Photoshop (Gimp)); Canvas; Redmine; Excel; Atom (HTML and CSS); GitHub

MEDIA COVERAGE

Research Featured in Volpe, Andrea. "Being Human Now: How Innovative Methods and Contemporary Concerns are Helping Humanities Scholars Re-Envision the Past and Imagine the Future." Colloquy. Spring 2016. 12-17.